If you asked me to dance, I'd probably freeze on the spot.
如果你邀请我跳舞，我可能会当场僵住。
I lack rhythm and coordination and some people say I have two left feet!
我缺乏节奏感和协调性，有人说我笨手笨脚的！
But with some persuasion and Dutch courage I can be tempted to take to the dance floor and shake some moves – and that, apparently, is only natural.
但在一些劝说和酒后壮胆的情况下，我可能会被引诱着走上舞池，扭动几下——而显然，这是很自然的事。
Experts have found as well as being fun, dancing might have helped us to survive as a species.
专家们发现，除了有趣，跳舞还可能帮助我们人类这个物种生存下来。
Evolutionary anthropologist Bronwyn Tarr from the University of Oxford has been telling the BBC World Service CrowdScience programme that when we dance with others, we are rewarded with feel-good endorphins that change how we feel about ourselves and those around us.
牛津大学的进化人类学家布朗温·塔尔在接受英国广播公司全球服务台《大众科学》节目采访时表示，当我们和他人一起跳舞时，大脑会分泌让人感觉愉悦的内啡肽，这种物质会改变我们对自己和周围人的看法。
Dancing alone is one thing but it's dancing as a group that makes our brain reward us with a cocktail of feel-good hormones and is likely to lead to profound social effects.
独自跳舞是一回事，但集体跳舞会让大脑分泌多种让人愉悦的荷尔蒙，还可能产生深远的社会影响。
It's being in sync with others that makes us happy.
与他人保持同步才是让我们感到快乐的关键。
She says that "dancing fosters social closeness between people. It helps us build social connections and communities.
她说：“跳舞能促进人与人之间的亲密关系，帮助我们建立社会联系和社群。
In our past, those social connections would have been critical for surviving."
在过去，这些社会联系对生存至关重要。”
You certainly need the right kind of music to help you shimmy, boogie or even twerk, but once you get the right beat and get into the groove with others, it can be an uplifting experience.
你当然需要合适的音乐来帮助你跳希米舞、布吉舞，甚至扭臀舞，但一旦找到合适的节奏，和其他人一起进入状态，这会是一种令人心情愉悦的体验。
Even my cringeworthy dad dancing makes me feel good sometimes.
即使是我那令人尴尬的“老爹式跳舞”，有时也会让我心情变好。
And in Swindon in the UK, this 'style' of dancing has been taken to a new level, where babies, attached to their fathers' chests in a sling, have been dancing with the aim of increasing the bond between parent and child.
在英国的斯温顿，这种跳舞“风格”被提升到了一个新高度——婴儿被用背带绑在父亲胸前，一起跳舞，目的是增进亲子之间的联系。
Dance is also a good way to keep fit and improve our mental health.
跳舞也是保持健康和改善心理健康的好方法。
In Wales there have been calls for doctors to prescribe dance classes to people who are unwell.
在威尔士，有人呼吁医生为身体不适的人开具舞蹈课程处方。
The Arts Council of Wales claims there are many health benefits.
威尔士艺术委员会称跳舞对健康有很多好处。
And Bronwyn Tarr says "more and more we're actually discovering that your longevity – your life expectancy – is predicted by the social connections that you have… still today it's something we should do more of."
布朗温·塔尔说：“我们越来越发现，一个人的寿命——也就是预期寿命——是由其拥有的社会联系决定的……即使在今天，这也是我们应该多做的事情。”
It could be part of being an uptight Englishman that makes me a reluctant dancer.
可能是因为我是个拘谨的英国人，所以才不情愿跳舞。
Look at other nationalities such as Cubans where dancing is at the heart of their cultural identity.
看看其他民族，比如古巴人，跳舞是他们文化认同的核心。
And in Brazil at Carnival time, people let their hair down by dancing together day and night.
而在巴西的狂欢节期间，人们不分昼夜地一起跳舞，放松身心。
They seem to be having a good time – so maybe I should get on my feet and dance!
他们看起来玩得很开心——所以也许我也应该站起来跳舞！